<Standard>
		  <Heading level="2"> <TitleText>Transmission Control Functions (Standard 102)</TitleText> <HistoricalNote> <ul> <li>[SOR/97-421, s. 3]</li> </ul> </HistoricalNote> </Heading> <Section> <Label>102.</Label> <Subsection> <Label>(1)</Label> <Text>Any automatic transmission fitted on a vehicle shall have</Text> <Paragraph> <Label>( <Emphasis style="italic">a</Emphasis> )</Label> <Text>its control positions in such a sequence that</Text> <Subparagraph> <Label>(i)</Label> <Text>movement between any forward and reverse drive position may be made only through a neutral position,</Text> </Subparagraph> <Subparagraph> <Label>(ii)</Label> <Text>in the case of a steering-column-mounted control, movement from the neutral position to any forward drive position may be made in a clockwise direction only, and</Text> </Subparagraph> <Subparagraph> <Label>(iii)</Label> <Text>the park position, if included in the sequence, is located at the end of the sequence adjacent to the reverse drive position; and</Text> </Subparagraph> </Paragraph> <Paragraph> <Label>( <Emphasis style="italic">b</Emphasis> )</Label> <Text>one forward drive position that, in vehicles having more than one forward transmission gear ratio, provides a greater degree of engine braking than the highest speed transmission ratio at speeds below 40 km/h.</Text> </Paragraph> </Subsection> <Subsection> <Label>(2)</Label> <Text>On any vehicle equipped with an automatic transmission, a motor used for the vehicle's propulsion must not be started by setting the ignition switch to the position used to start the motor if the transmission control is in a forward or reverse drive position.</Text> </Subsection> <Subsection> <Label>(2.1)</Label> <Text>If a passenger car, multi-purpose passenger vehicle, truck or three-wheeled vehicle has a GVWR of 4 536 kg or less and a transmission control sequence that includes a park position, the transmission control must not be capable of shifting from the park position to the forward or reverse drive position — while a motor used for the vehicle's propulsion is in use — unless the service brake pedal is depressed or the service brakes are otherwise engaged.</Text> </Subsection> <Subsection> <Label>(3)</Label> <Text>Subject to subsection (5), where the transmission control sequence includes a park position, the identification of the transmission control positions and the position selected shall be displayed in at least a single location in view of the driver when</Text> <Paragraph> <Label>( <Emphasis style="italic">a</Emphasis> )</Label> <Text>the ignition switch is set to the position where the transmission can be shifted; or</Text> </Paragraph> <Paragraph> <Label>( <Emphasis style="italic">b</Emphasis> )</Label> <Text>the transmission control is not in the park position.</Text> </Paragraph> </Subsection> <Subsection> <Label>(4)</Label> <Text>Subject to subsection (5), if the transmission control sequence does not include a park position, the identification of the transmission control positions and the position selected shall be displayed in at least a single location in view of the driver when the ignition switch is set to the position where the engine is capable of operation.</Text> </Subsection> <Subsection> <Label>(5)</Label> <Text>The identification of transmission control positions need not be displayed when the ignition switch is set to the position used to start the vehicle.</Text> </Subsection> <Subsection> <Label>(6)</Label> <Text>The identification of the transmission control positions and sequence, on vehicles equipped with a manual transmission, shall be permanently displayed in view of the driver.</Text> </Subsection> <Subsection> <Label>(7)</Label> <Text>If a passenger car, multi-purpose passenger vehicle, truck or three-wheeled vehicle has a GVWR of 4 536 kg or less and is equipped with a manual transmission, a motor used for the vehicle's propulsion must not be started by setting the ignition switch to the position used to start the motor unless the clutch pedal is depressed or the drive train is otherwise disengaged.</Text> </Subsection> <Subsection> <Label>(8)</Label> <Text>In this section, <DefinedTermEn>drive train</DefinedTermEn> means the components that transfer motive power from the motor to the drive wheels.</Text> </Subsection> <HistoricalNote> <ul> <li>SOR/95-164, s. 4;</li> <li>SOR/97-421, ss. 4, 22(F);</li> <li>SOR/2003-189, s. 1;</li> <li>SOR/2003-272, s. 34;</li> <li>SOR/2006-94, s. 4(E);</li> <li>SOR/2007-246, s. 2.</li> </ul> </HistoricalNote> </Section> <Heading level="2"> <TitleText>Windshield Defrosting and Defogging</TitleText> </Heading> <Section> <Label>103.</Label> <Subsection> <Label>(1)</Label> <Text>In this section,</Text> <Definition generate-in-text="no"> <Text> <DefinedTermEn>critical area</DefinedTermEn> means area C as referred to in section 104 of this Schedule; ( <DefinedTermFr>zone critique</DefinedTermFr> )</Text> </Definition> <Definition generate-in-text="no"> <Text> <DefinedTermEn>defog</DefinedTermEn> means to remove moisture from the inside surface of the glass; ( <DefinedTermFr>désembuer</DefinedTermFr> )</Text> </Definition> <Definition generate-in-text="no"> <Text> <DefinedTermEn>defrost</DefinedTermEn> means to melt frost or ice on the inside or outside surface of the glass; ( <DefinedTermFr>dégivrer</DefinedTermFr> )</Text> </Definition> <Definition generate-in-text="no"> <Text> <DefinedTermEn>entire windshield</DefinedTermEn> means area A as referred to in section 104 of this Schedule; ( <DefinedTermFr>pare-brise tout entier</DefinedTermFr> )</Text> </Definition> <Definition generate-in-text="no"> <Text> <DefinedTermEn>road load</DefinedTermEn> means the power output required to move the vehicle at the curb mass plus 180 kg on level, clean, dry, smooth portland cement concrete pavement or other surface with an equivalent coefficient of surface friction at a specified speed through still air at 20°C and a standard barometric pressure of 101.3 kPa, and includes driveline friction, rolling friction and air resistance. ( <DefinedTermFr>charge de route</DefinedTermFr> )</Text> </Definition> </Subsection> <Subsection> <Label>(2)</Label> <Text>Subject to subsection (2.1), every vehicle shall be equipped with a windshield defrosting and defogging system.</Text> </Subsection> <Subsection> <Label>(2.1)</Label> <Text>A three-wheeled vehicle that is equipped with a windshield shall be equipped with a windshield defrosting and defogging system.</Text> </Subsection> <Subsection> <Label>(3)</Label> <Text>In the case of a passenger car or a three-wheeled vehicle, the windshield defrosting and defogging system shall</Text> <Paragraph> <Label>( <Emphasis style="italic">a</Emphasis> )</Label> <Text>meet the requirements of section 3 of SAE Recommended Practice J902 Passenger Car Windshield Defrosting Systems, (August 1964), when tested in accordance with paragraph ( <Emphasis style="italic">b</Emphasis> ) except that the areas referred to in that section as "critical area" and "entire windshield" shall be as referred to in subsection (1) of this section; and</Text> </Paragraph> <Paragraph> <Label>( <Emphasis style="italic">b</Emphasis> )</Label> <Text>be tested in accordance with such of the portions of paragraphs 4.1 to 4.4.7 of SAE Recommended Practice J902, (August 1964), or SAE Recommended Practice J902 <Emphasis style="italic">a</Emphasis> , (March 1967), as are applicable to that system.</Text> </Paragraph> </Subsection> <Subsection> <Label>(4)</Label> <Text>Despite the testing requirements set out in subsection (3) for the windshield defrosting and defogging system of a passenger car or three-wheeled vehicle,</Text> <Paragraph> <Label>( <Emphasis style="italic">a</Emphasis> )</Label> <Text>in the case of a passenger car or three-wheeled vehicle equipped with a heating system other than a heat exchanger type that uses the engine's coolant as a means to supply the heat to the heat exchanger, the procedure specified by the vehicle's manufacturer for cold weather starting shall be followed during the entire test period, except that the use of a power or heat source external to the vehicle is not permitted;</Text> </Paragraph> <Paragraph> <Label>( <Emphasis style="italic">b</Emphasis> )</Label> <Text>in the case of all other passenger cars and three-wheeled vehicles,</Text> <Subparagraph> <Label>(i)</Label> <Text>during the entire test period, the engine speed shall not exceed 1,500 revolutions per minute in neutral gear or the engine speed and load shall not exceed the speed and load at 40 km/h (25 miles per hour) in the manufacturer's recommended gear with road load, or</Text> </Subparagraph> <Subparagraph> <Label>(ii)</Label> <Text>during the first 5 minutes of the test period, the warm-up procedure recommended by the vehicle's manufacturer for cold weather starting shall be followed and during the last 35 minutes of the test period, the procedure referred to in subparagraph (i) shall be followed;</Text> </Subparagraph> </Paragraph> <Paragraph> <Label>( <Emphasis style="italic">c</Emphasis> )</Label> <Text>a room air change of 90 times per hour is not required;</Text> </Paragraph> <Paragraph> <Label>( <Emphasis style="italic">d</Emphasis> )</Label> <Text>the windshield wipers may be used during the test if they are operated without manual assistance;</Text> </Paragraph> <Paragraph> <Label>( <Emphasis style="italic">e</Emphasis> )</Label> <Text>one or two windows may be open a total of 25 mm;</Text> </Paragraph> <Paragraph> <Label>( <Emphasis style="italic">f</Emphasis> )</Label> <Text>the defroster blower may be turned on at any time;</Text> </Paragraph> <Paragraph> <Label>( <Emphasis style="italic">g</Emphasis> )</Label> <Text>the wind velocity is at any level from 0 to 3 km/h; and</Text> </Paragraph> <Paragraph> <Label>( <Emphasis style="italic">h</Emphasis> )</Label> <Text>the test chamber temperature and the wind velocity shall be measured after the engine has been started, at the forwardmost point of the vehicle or a point 91.4 cm (36 inches) from the base of the windshield, whichever is farther forward, at a level halfway between the top and the bottom of the windshield on the vehicle centreline.</Text> </Paragraph> </Subsection> <HistoricalNote> <ul> <li>SOR/97-264, s. 1;</li> <li>SOR/2003-272, s. 8;</li> <li>SOR/2008-104, s. 9.</li> </ul> </HistoricalNote> </Section> <Heading level="2"> <TitleText>Windshield Wiping and Washing System</TitleText> </Heading> <Section> <Label>104.</Label> <Subsection> <Label>(1)</Label> <Text>In this section,</Text> <Definition generate-in-text="no"> <Text> <DefinedTermEn>areas A, B and C</DefinedTermEn> means the areas referred to in Column I of Tables I, II, III and IV to this section when established as shown in Figures 1 and 2 of SAE Recommended Practice J903 <Emphasis style="italic">a</Emphasis> Passenger Car Windshield Wiper Systems, (May 1966), using the angles specified in Columns III to VI of the above Tables; ( <DefinedTermFr>zones A, B et C</DefinedTermFr> )</Text> </Definition> <Definition generate-in-text="no"> <Text> <DefinedTermEn>daylight opening</DefinedTermEn> means the maximum unobstructed opening through the glazing surface as defined in paragraph 2.3.12 of Section E, Ground Vehicle Practice, SAE Aerospace-Automotive Drawing Standards, (September 1963); ( <DefinedTermFr>ouverture de jour</DefinedTermFr> )</Text> </Definition> <Definition generate-in-text="no"> <Text> <DefinedTermEn>glazing surface reference line</DefinedTermEn> means the intersection of the glazing surface and a horizontal plane 635 mm above the seating reference point, as shown in Figure 1 of SAE Recommended Practice J903 <Emphasis style="italic">a</Emphasis> (May 1966); ( <DefinedTermFr>ligne de référence de la surface vitrée</DefinedTermFr> )</Text> </Definition> <Definition generate-in-text="no"> <Text> <DefinedTermEn>overall width</DefinedTermEn> means the maximum overall body width dimension W116 as defined in Section E, Ground Vehicle Practice, SAE Aerospace-Automotive Drawing Standards, (September 1963); ( <DefinedTermFr>largeur hors tout</DefinedTermFr> )</Text> </Definition> <Definition generate-in-text="no"> <Text> <DefinedTermEn>plan view reference line</DefinedTermEn> means,</Text> <Paragraph> <Label>( <Emphasis style="italic">a</Emphasis> )</Label> <Text>in respect of vehicles with a bench type front seat, a line parallel to the longitudinal centreline of the vehicle and outboard of the centre of the steering wheel by a distance equal to 0.15 times the difference between one-half the shoulder room dimension and the steering wheel centre offset, as shown in Figure 2 of SAE Recommended Practice J903 <Emphasis style="italic">a</Emphasis> , (May 1966); and</Text> </Paragraph> <Paragraph> <Label>( <Emphasis style="italic">b</Emphasis> )</Label> <Text>in respect of vehicles with individual front seats,</Text> <Subparagraph> <Label>(i)</Label> <Text>a line parallel to the longitudinal centreline of the vehicle which passes through the centre of the driver's designated seating position, or</Text> </Subparagraph> <Subparagraph> <Label>(ii)</Label> <Text>a line parallel to the longitudinal centreline of the vehicle located so that the geometric centre of the 95 per cent eye range contour is positioned on the longitudinal centreline of the driver's designated seating position; ( <DefinedTermFr>ligne de référence longitudinale</DefinedTermFr> )</Text> </Subparagraph> </Paragraph> </Definition> <Definition generate-in-text="no"> <Text> <DefinedTermEn>shoulder room dimension</DefinedTermEn> means the front shoulder room dimension W3 as defined in Section E, Ground Vehicle Practice, SAE Aerospace-Automotive Drawing Standards, (September 1963); ( <DefinedTermFr>espace d'épaules</DefinedTermFr> )</Text> </Definition> <Definition generate-in-text="no"> <Text> <DefinedTermEn>95 per cent eye range contour</DefinedTermEn> means the 95th percentile tangential cut-off specified in SAE Recommended Practice J941 <Emphasis style="italic">a</Emphasis> Passenger Car Driver's Eye Range, (August 1967). ( <DefinedTermFr>95 pour cent du contour de portée visuelle</DefinedTermFr> )</Text> </Definition> </Subsection> <Subsection> <Label>(2)</Label> <Text>For the purposes of this section, the expressions "manikin H-point", "manikin H-point with seat in rearmost position", and "H-point" used in an SAE Standard or SAE Recommended Practice mean "seating reference point".</Text> </Subsection> <Subsection> <Label>(3)</Label> <Text>Subject to subsection (3.1), every vehicle shall have a power-driven windshield wiping system that has at least two frequencies or speeds and that has, irrespective of engine speed and engine load,</Text> <Paragraph> <Label>( <Emphasis style="italic">a</Emphasis> )</Label> <Text>one frequency or speed of at least 45 cycles per minute;</Text> </Paragraph> <Paragraph> <Label>( <Emphasis style="italic">b</Emphasis> )</Label> <Text>a difference of at least 15 cycles per minute between the highest frequency or speed and one of the lower frequencies or speeds; and</Text> </Paragraph> <Paragraph> <Label>( <Emphasis style="italic">c</Emphasis> )</Label> <Text>the lower frequency or speed referred to in paragraph ( <Emphasis style="italic">b</Emphasis> ) equal to at least 20 cycles per minute.</Text> </Paragraph> </Subsection> <Subsection> <Label>(3.1)</Label> <Text>A three-wheeled vehicle that is equipped with a windshield shall have a windshield wiping system that conforms to the requirements of subsection (3).</Text> </Subsection> <Subsection> <Label>(4)</Label> <Text>Compliance with subsection (3) shall be demonstrated by testing under the conditions specified in sections 4.1.1 and 4.1.2 of SAE Recommended Practice J903 <Emphasis style="italic">a</Emphasis> , (May 1966).</Text> </Subsection> <Subsection> <Label>(5)</Label> <Text>In the case of a passenger car or a three-wheeled vehicle, the windshield wiping system, when tested wet in accordance with SAE Recommended Practice J903a (May 1966), shall wipe the percentage of areas A, B and C of the windshield that</Text> <Paragraph> <Label>( <Emphasis style="italic">a</Emphasis> )</Label> <Text>is specified in Column II of whichever of Tables I, II, III or IV to this section is applicable; and</Text> </Paragraph> <Paragraph> <Label>( <Emphasis style="italic">b</Emphasis> )</Label> <Text>is within the area bounded by a perimeter line on the glazing surface 25 mm from the edge of the daylight opening.</Text> </Paragraph> </Subsection> <Subsection> <Label>(6)</Label> <Text>Subject to subsection (7), every vehicle shall have a windshield washing system that meets the requirements of SAE Recommended Practice J942, <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Passenger Car Windshield Washer Systems</XRefExternal> (November 1965), except that the words "the effective wipe pattern defined in SAE J903, paragraph 3.1.2" in paragraph 3.1 of SAE Recommended Practice J942 shall be replaced</Text> <Paragraph> <Label>( <Emphasis style="italic">a</Emphasis> )</Label> <Text>in the case of a passenger car or a three-wheeled vehicle, by the words "the areas established in accordance with the definition of areas A, B and C in subsection (1) of Canada Motor Vehicle Safety Standard No. 104"; and</Text> </Paragraph> <Paragraph> <Label>( <Emphasis style="italic">b</Emphasis> )</Label> <Text>in the case of a multi-purpose passenger vehicle, truck or bus, by the words "the pattern designed by the manufacturer for the windshield wiping system on the exterior surface of the windshield glazing".</Text> </Paragraph> </Subsection> <Subsection> <Label>(7)</Label> <Text>A three-wheeled vehicle that is equipped with a windshield shall have a windshield washing system that meets the requirements of subsection (6).</Text> </Subsection> <Subsection> <Label/> <Text/> <TableGroup pointsize="10" spanlanguages="yes" spanmarginalnotecol="yes" topmarginspacing="4"> <Caption position="over" justification="center"> TABLE I </Caption> <table frame="topbot"> <title justification="center">PASSENGER CARS AND THREE-WHEELED VEHICLES OF LESS THAN 1 520 MM OVERALL WIDTH</title> <tgroup cols="6" align="left" keep-together="yes"> <colspec colname="1" colwidth="83.46*" htmlwidth="18%"/> <colspec colname="2" colwidth="100.20*" htmlwidth="21%"/> <colspec colname="3" colwidth="72.34*" htmlwidth="15%"/> <colspec colname="4" colwidth="75.76*" htmlwidth="16%"/> <colspec colname="5" colwidth="68.30*" htmlwidth="15%"/> <colspec colname="6" colwidth="67.99*" htmlwidth="15%"/> <thead> <row topdouble="yes" topmarginspacing="4"> <entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="top" id="t3805h0">Column I</entry> <entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="top" id="t3805h1">Column II</entry> <entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="center" valign="top" id="t3805h2">Column III</entry> <entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="center" valign="top" id="t3805h3">Column IV</entry> <entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="center" valign="top" id="t3805h4">Column V</entry> <entry colname="6" colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="center" valign="top" id="t3805h5">Column VI</entry> </row> <row> <entry morerows="1" colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom" id="t3805h6" headers="t3805h0">Area</entry> <entry morerows="1" colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom" id="t3805h7" headers="t3805h1">Minimum Percentage to be wiped</entry> <entry namest="3" nameend="6" colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="center" id="t3805h8" headers="t3805h2 t3805h3 t3805h4 t3805h5">Angle in degrees</entry> </row> <row> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="center" valign="bottom" id="t3805h9" headers="t3805h2 t3805h8">Left</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="center" valign="bottom" id="t3805h10" headers="t3805h3 t3805h8">Right</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="center" valign="bottom" id="t3805h11" headers="t3805h4 t3805h8">Up</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="center" valign="bottom" id="t3805h12" headers="t3805h5 t3805h8">Down</entry> </row> </thead> <tbody> <row> <entry rowheader="yes" colsep="0" rowsep="0" id="t3805h13" headers="t3805h0 t3805h6">A <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot"/> </entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" headers="t3805h0 t3805h6 t3805h13 t3805h1 t3805h7">80</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3805h0 t3805h6 t3805h13 t3805h2 t3805h8 t3805h9">16</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3805h0 t3805h6 t3805h13 t3805h3 t3805h8 t3805h10">49</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3805h0 t3805h6 t3805h13 t3805h4 t3805h8 t3805h11">7</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3805h0 t3805h6 t3805h13 t3805h5 t3805h8 t3805h12">5</entry> </row> <row> <entry rowheader="yes" colsep="0" rowsep="0" id="t3805h19" headers="t3805h0 t3805h6">B <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot"/> </entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" headers="t3805h0 t3805h6 t3805h19 t3805h1 t3805h7">94</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3805h0 t3805h6 t3805h19 t3805h2 t3805h8 t3805h9">13</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3805h0 t3805h6 t3805h19 t3805h3 t3805h8 t3805h10">46</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3805h0 t3805h6 t3805h19 t3805h4 t3805h8 t3805h11">4</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3805h0 t3805h6 t3805h19 t3805h5 t3805h8 t3805h12">3</entry> </row> <row> <entry rowheader="yes" colsep="0" rowsep="0" id="t3805h25" headers="t3805h0 t3805h6">C <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot"/> </entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" headers="t3805h0 t3805h6 t3805h25 t3805h1 t3805h7">99</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3805h0 t3805h6 t3805h25 t3805h2 t3805h8 t3805h9">7</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3805h0 t3805h6 t3805h25 t3805h3 t3805h8 t3805h10">15</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3805h0 t3805h6 t3805h25 t3805h4 t3805h8 t3805h11">3</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3805h0 t3805h6 t3805h25 t3805h5 t3805h8 t3805h12">1</entry> </row> </tbody> </tgroup> </table> </TableGroup> <TableGroup pointsize="10" spanlanguages="yes" spanmarginalnotecol="yes" topmarginspacing="4"> <Caption position="over" justification="center"> TABLE II </Caption> <table frame="topbot"> <title justification="center">PASSENGER CARS AND THREE-WHEELED VEHICLES OF 1 520 MM OR MORE BUT LESS THAN 1 630 MM OVERALL WIDTH</title> <tgroup cols="6" align="left" keep-together="yes"> <colspec colname="1" colwidth="83.16*" htmlwidth="18%"/> <colspec colname="2" colwidth="101.10*" htmlwidth="22%"/> <colspec colname="3" colwidth="71.90*" htmlwidth="15%"/> <colspec colname="4" colwidth="75.96*" htmlwidth="16%"/> <colspec colname="5" colwidth="67.84*" htmlwidth="14%"/> <colspec colname="6" colwidth="68.11*" htmlwidth="15%"/> <thead> <row topdouble="yes" topmarginspacing="4"> <entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="top" id="t3806h0">Column I</entry> <entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="top" id="t3806h1">Column II</entry> <entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="center" valign="top" id="t3806h2">Column III</entry> <entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="center" valign="top" id="t3806h3">Column IV</entry> <entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="center" valign="top" id="t3806h4">Column V</entry> <entry colname="6" colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="center" valign="top" id="t3806h5">Column VI</entry> </row> <row> <entry morerows="1" colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom" id="t3806h6" headers="t3806h0">Area</entry> <entry morerows="1" colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom" id="t3806h7" headers="t3806h1">Minimum Percentage to be wiped</entry> <entry namest="3" nameend="6" colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="center" id="t3806h8" headers="t3806h2 t3806h3 t3806h4 t3806h5">Angle in degrees</entry> </row> <row> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="center" valign="bottom" id="t3806h9" headers="t3806h2 t3806h8">Left</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="center" valign="bottom" id="t3806h10" headers="t3806h3 t3806h8">Right</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="center" valign="bottom" id="t3806h11" headers="t3806h4 t3806h8">Up</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="center" valign="bottom" id="t3806h12" headers="t3806h5 t3806h8">Down</entry> </row> </thead> <tbody> <row> <entry rowheader="yes" colsep="0" rowsep="0" id="t3806h13" headers="t3806h0 t3806h6">A <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot"/> </entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" headers="t3806h0 t3806h6 t3806h13 t3806h1 t3806h7">80</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3806h0 t3806h6 t3806h13 t3806h2 t3806h8 t3806h9">17</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3806h0 t3806h6 t3806h13 t3806h3 t3806h8 t3806h10">51</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3806h0 t3806h6 t3806h13 t3806h4 t3806h8 t3806h11">8</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3806h0 t3806h6 t3806h13 t3806h5 t3806h8 t3806h12">5</entry> </row> <row> <entry rowheader="yes" colsep="0" rowsep="0" id="t3806h19" headers="t3806h0 t3806h6">B <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot"/> </entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" headers="t3806h0 t3806h6 t3806h19 t3806h1 t3806h7">94</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3806h0 t3806h6 t3806h19 t3806h2 t3806h8 t3806h9">13</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3806h0 t3806h6 t3806h19 t3806h3 t3806h8 t3806h10">49</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3806h0 t3806h6 t3806h19 t3806h4 t3806h8 t3806h11">4</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3806h0 t3806h6 t3806h19 t3806h5 t3806h8 t3806h12">3</entry> </row> <row> <entry rowheader="yes" colsep="0" rowsep="0" id="t3806h25" headers="t3806h0 t3806h6">C <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot"/> </entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" headers="t3806h0 t3806h6 t3806h25 t3806h1 t3806h7">99</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3806h0 t3806h6 t3806h25 t3806h2 t3806h8 t3806h9">7</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3806h0 t3806h6 t3806h25 t3806h3 t3806h8 t3806h10">15</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3806h0 t3806h6 t3806h25 t3806h4 t3806h8 t3806h11">3</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3806h0 t3806h6 t3806h25 t3806h5 t3806h8 t3806h12">1</entry> </row> </tbody> </tgroup> </table> </TableGroup> <TableGroup pointsize="10" spanlanguages="yes" spanmarginalnotecol="yes" topmarginspacing="4"> <Caption position="over" justification="center"> TABLE III </Caption> <table frame="topbot"> <title justification="center">PASSENGER CARS AND THREE-WHEELED VEHICLES OF 1 630 MM OR MORE BUT LESS THAN 1 730 MM OVERALL WIDTH</title> <tgroup cols="6" align="left" keep-together="yes"> <colspec colname="1" colwidth="83.76*" htmlwidth="18%"/> <colspec colname="2" colwidth="100.50*" htmlwidth="21%"/> <colspec colname="3" colwidth="71.97*" htmlwidth="15%"/> <colspec colname="4" colwidth="76.04*" htmlwidth="16%"/> <colspec colname="5" colwidth="67.63*" htmlwidth="14%"/> <colspec colname="6" colwidth="68.17*" htmlwidth="15%"/> <thead> <row topdouble="yes" topmarginspacing="4"> <entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="top" id="t3807h0">Column I</entry> <entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="top" id="t3807h1">Column II</entry> <entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="center" valign="top" id="t3807h2">Column III</entry> <entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="center" valign="top" id="t3807h3">Column IV</entry> <entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="center" valign="top" id="t3807h4">Column V</entry> <entry colname="6" colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="center" valign="top" id="t3807h5">Column VI</entry> </row> <row> <entry morerows="1" colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom" id="t3807h6" headers="t3807h0">Area</entry> <entry morerows="1" colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom" id="t3807h7" headers="t3807h1">Minimum Percentage to be wiped</entry> <entry namest="3" nameend="6" colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="center" id="t3807h8" headers="t3807h2 t3807h3 t3807h4 t3807h5">Angle in degrees</entry> </row> <row> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="center" valign="bottom" id="t3807h9" headers="t3807h2 t3807h8">Left</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="center" valign="bottom" id="t3807h10" headers="t3807h3 t3807h8">Right</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="center" valign="bottom" id="t3807h11" headers="t3807h4 t3807h8">Up</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="center" valign="bottom" id="t3807h12" headers="t3807h5 t3807h8">Down</entry> </row> </thead> <tbody> <row> <entry rowheader="yes" colsep="0" rowsep="0" id="t3807h13" headers="t3807h0 t3807h6">A <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot"/> </entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" headers="t3807h0 t3807h6 t3807h13 t3807h1 t3807h7">80</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3807h0 t3807h6 t3807h13 t3807h2 t3807h8 t3807h9">17</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3807h0 t3807h6 t3807h13 t3807h3 t3807h8 t3807h10">53</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3807h0 t3807h6 t3807h13 t3807h4 t3807h8 t3807h11">9</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3807h0 t3807h6 t3807h13 t3807h5 t3807h8 t3807h12">5</entry> </row> <row> <entry rowheader="yes" colsep="0" rowsep="0" id="t3807h19" headers="t3807h0 t3807h6">B <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot"/> </entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" headers="t3807h0 t3807h6 t3807h19 t3807h1 t3807h7">94</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3807h0 t3807h6 t3807h19 t3807h2 t3807h8 t3807h9">14</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3807h0 t3807h6 t3807h19 t3807h3 t3807h8 t3807h10">51</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3807h0 t3807h6 t3807h19 t3807h4 t3807h8 t3807h11">5</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3807h0 t3807h6 t3807h19 t3807h5 t3807h8 t3807h12">3</entry> </row> <row> <entry rowheader="yes" colsep="0" rowsep="0" id="t3807h25" headers="t3807h0 t3807h6">C <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot"/> </entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" headers="t3807h0 t3807h6 t3807h25 t3807h1 t3807h7">99</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3807h0 t3807h6 t3807h25 t3807h2 t3807h8 t3807h9">8</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3807h0 t3807h6 t3807h25 t3807h3 t3807h8 t3807h10">15</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3807h0 t3807h6 t3807h25 t3807h4 t3807h8 t3807h11">4</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3807h0 t3807h6 t3807h25 t3807h5 t3807h8 t3807h12">1</entry> </row> </tbody> </tgroup> </table> </TableGroup> <TableGroup pointsize="10" spanlanguages="yes" spanmarginalnotecol="yes" topmarginspacing="4"> <Caption position="over" justification="center"> TABLE IV </Caption> <table frame="topbot"> <title justification="center">PASSENGER CARS AND THREE-WHEELED VEHICLES OF 1 730 MM OR MORE OVERALL WIDTH</title> <tgroup cols="6" align="left" keep-together="yes"> <colspec colname="1" colwidth="83.46*" htmlwidth="18%"/> <colspec colname="2" colwidth="99.91*" htmlwidth="21%"/> <colspec colname="3" colwidth="71.92*" htmlwidth="15%"/> <colspec colname="4" colwidth="76.55*" htmlwidth="16%"/> <colspec colname="5" colwidth="67.84*" htmlwidth="14%"/> <colspec colname="6" colwidth="68.39*" htmlwidth="15%"/> <thead> <row topdouble="yes" topmarginspacing="4"> <entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="top" id="t3808h0">Column I</entry> <entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="top" id="t3808h1">Column II</entry> <entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="center" valign="top" id="t3808h2">Column III</entry> <entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="center" valign="top" id="t3808h3">Column IV</entry> <entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="center" valign="top" id="t3808h4">Column V</entry> <entry colname="6" colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="center" valign="top" id="t3808h5">Column VI</entry> </row> <row> <entry morerows="1" colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom" id="t3808h6" headers="t3808h0">Area</entry> <entry morerows="1" colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom" id="t3808h7" headers="t3808h1">Minimum Percentage to be wiped</entry> <entry namest="3" nameend="6" colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="center" id="t3808h8" headers="t3808h2 t3808h3 t3808h4 t3808h5">Angle in degrees</entry> </row> <row> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="center" valign="bottom" id="t3808h9" headers="t3808h2 t3808h8">Left</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="center" valign="bottom" id="t3808h10" headers="t3808h3 t3808h8">Right</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="center" valign="bottom" id="t3808h11" headers="t3808h4 t3808h8">Up</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="center" valign="bottom" id="t3808h12" headers="t3808h5 t3808h8">Down</entry> </row> </thead> <tbody> <row> <entry rowheader="yes" colsep="0" rowsep="0" id="t3808h13" headers="t3808h0 t3808h6">A <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot"/> </entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" headers="t3808h0 t3808h6 t3808h13 t3808h1 t3808h7">80</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3808h0 t3808h6 t3808h13 t3808h2 t3808h8 t3808h9">18</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3808h0 t3808h6 t3808h13 t3808h3 t3808h8 t3808h10">56</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3808h0 t3808h6 t3808h13 t3808h4 t3808h8 t3808h11">10</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3808h0 t3808h6 t3808h13 t3808h5 t3808h8 t3808h12">5</entry> </row> <row> <entry rowheader="yes" colsep="0" rowsep="0" id="t3808h19" headers="t3808h0 t3808h6">B <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot"/> </entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" headers="t3808h0 t3808h6 t3808h19 t3808h1 t3808h7">94</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3808h0 t3808h6 t3808h19 t3808h2 t3808h8 t3808h9">14</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3808h0 t3808h6 t3808h19 t3808h3 t3808h8 t3808h10">53</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3808h0 t3808h6 t3808h19 t3808h4 t3808h8 t3808h11">5</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3808h0 t3808h6 t3808h19 t3808h5 t3808h8 t3808h12">3</entry> </row> <row> <entry rowheader="yes" colsep="0" rowsep="0" id="t3808h25" headers="t3808h0 t3808h6">C <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot"/> </entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" headers="t3808h0 t3808h6 t3808h25 t3808h1 t3808h7">99</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3808h0 t3808h6 t3808h25 t3808h2 t3808h8 t3808h9">10</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3808h0 t3808h6 t3808h25 t3808h3 t3808h8 t3808h10">15</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3808h0 t3808h6 t3808h25 t3808h4 t3808h8 t3808h11">5</entry> <entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="center" headers="t3808h0 t3808h6 t3808h25 t3808h5 t3808h8 t3808h12">1</entry> </row> </tbody> </tgroup> </table> </TableGroup> </Subsection> <HistoricalNote> <ul> <li>SOR/94-670, s. 2(F);</li> <li>SOR/97-264, s. 2;</li> <li>SOR/2002-55, s. 21;</li> <li>SOR/2003-272, s. 9;</li> <li>SOR/2006-94, s. 4(E);</li> <li>SOR/2008-104, s. 10.</li> </ul> </HistoricalNote> </Section>
</Standard>
